Library. University Librarian. Administrative files UARC.0377
UCLA Library Special Collections
Library. University Librarian. Administrative files
1919-1998
UCLA Library Special Collections
UARC.0377
249.4 linear feet (291 boxes and 133 cartons)
Record Series 377 contains the administrative files of the UCLA University Librarian generated between 1919 and 1998.
Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. Advance notice required for access. Contact the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk for paging information.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
COLLECTION CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. TO access digital materials you must notify the reference desk in advance of your visit. COLLECTION CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9935211183606533
We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form located on our website: Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special Collections.
Historical note
The position of University Librarian has been held by the following individuals:
Elizabeth Fargo - 1910-1923
John E. Goodwin - 1923-1944
Lawrence Clark Powell - 1944-1961
Robert Vosper - 1961-1973
Page Ackerman - 1973-1977
Russell Shank - 1977–1990
Gloria Werner - 1990–2002
Gary E. Strong - 2003–2013
Viginia Steele - 2013-present
Scope and Content
Record Series 377 contains the administrative files of the UCLA University Librarian, generated between 1919 and 1998, including those of John E. Goodwin, Lawrence Clark Powell, and Robert Vosper. Files regard such topics as library departments; branch libraries; interaction and cooperation with UCLA academic departments, other University of California campuses, libraries, universities, and institutions; acquisitions; budgets; committees; associations and societies; Library Council; Northern and Southern Regional Library Boards; Special Collections; programs and conferences; contracts; grants; the use and need of space; library visitors; bibliographers; OCLC (Online Computer Library Center, Inc., formerly the Ohio College Library Center); lending privileges; public library catalogs; and blanket purchase orders. Also included are the chronological files of James R. Cox (Acting Associate University Librarian for Public Services, 1977-1979; Assistant to the University Librarian, 1979-1983). Materials include correspondence, statistics, reports (annual, semiannual, quarterly, and monthly from library departments and branch libraries), meeting agendas and minutes, forms, manuals, and other operational materials.
This is an active record series; additional University records are expected to be added.
- Returned mail., 1936-1937.; 895037 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- British empire collection: A-Mz, 1934-1948.; 895036 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- British empire collection: Na-Manitoba., 1934-1937.; 895035 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Albania--Guatemala., 1934-1938.; 895034 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Haiti--Panama., 1925-1966.; 895033 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Peru--Yugoslavia., 1934-1941.; 895032 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- U.S. A--National Com., 1934-1938.; 895031 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- U.S. National Con.--Z., 1934-1937.; 895030 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- California A--Z., 1931-1938.; 895029 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- C--Z folders., 1935-1938.; 895028 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- To be filed., 895027 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Obituary collection., 1936.; 895026 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Forms., 1934-1936.; 895025 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Mrs. Troutt., 1934-1935.; 895024 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Newspaper., 895023 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Insulating and acoustic materials., 1936.; 895022 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Political collection - returned mail., 1936-1938.; 895021 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Science, A--Z., 1935-1937.; 895020 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- A1., 1944-1949.; 895019 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Academic Senate., 1964.; 895018 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Acessions book fund., 1933-1934.; 895017 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Accounting Department sheets., 1938-1950.; 895016 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Accounting, 1945-1948; 895015 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Acquisitions, includes code and personnel, 1934-1949; 895014 (Box 10, Folder 2-6)
- Acquisitions notes and replies, 1946-1952; 895011 (Box 10, Folder 7-9)
- Adler (Guido) Music Library, 1948-1949; 895009 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Agriculture, 1932-1949; 895008 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Aid to war areas, 1945; 895007 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- American Library Association, 1947-1949; 895006 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- American Library Association, 1944-1947; 1441057 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
- Annual Reports, 1931-1933; 1441062 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Anthropology and Sociology, 1945-1947; 1441073 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Area Language Army Specialized Training Program (ASTP), 1943-1944; 1441078 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Argus Bookstore, 1944-1947; 895004 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Army and Navy, 1941-1944; 895003 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Army map service, 1945-1946; 895002 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Art, 1944-1948; 895000 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Association of Research Libraries, 1932; 1946-1951; 1441082 (Box 11, Folder 10-12)
- Building completion (Remodeling and Alterations College/Powell Library), 1944-1949; 895005 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Association of Research Libraries - correspondence and miscellaneous reports., 1937-1949.; 894998 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
- Association of College and Reference Libraries - Nominating Committee., 1947-1948.; 894996 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Association of Research Libraries meeting., 1947.; 894995 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Associated students., 1945-1948.; 894994 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Astronomy., 1938-1946.; 894993 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Austrailian collection., 1944-1945.; 894992 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Auxillzry study halls., 1947-1948.; 894991 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- B., 1944-1949.; 894990 (Box 12, Folder 9-10)
- Berkeley., 1941-1949.; 894988 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Bibliography, punched cards., 1949.; 894987 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Bibliography room., 1946-1950.; 894986 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Book allotments., 1920-1927.; 894985 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Book chairman, departments, 1944-1949.; 894984 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Book funds, expenditures., 1932-1948.; 894983 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Book plates., 1923-1941.; 894982 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Binding., 1932-1950.; 894981 (Box 13, Folder 5-6)
- Bindery Committee., 1946-1948.; 894980 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- British Empire Collection., 1944-1945.; 894979 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- British Sessional Papers., 1939.; 894978 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Bruin., 1947-1949.; 894977 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Bryant., 1946-1949.; 894976 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Buidlings and grounds., 1944-1950.; 894975 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Building completion, faculty letters., 1944-1948.; 894974 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Building administration., 1949.; 894973 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Business office., 1941-1949.; 894972 (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Bynum Lindley., 1944-1945.; 894971 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- C., 1944-1947.; 894970 (Box 14, Folder 10)
- C., 1945-1947.; 894969 (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Care Book Program., 1949-1950.; 894968 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- California Bookman., 1946.; 894967 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- California Library Associaton annual meeting and Activity Committee., 1944-1947.; 894966 (Box 15, Folder 3-4)
- Chemistry., 1947.; 894964 (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Children's books., 1945.; 894963 (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Chuquet Library., 1920-1927.; 894962 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Circulation., 1924-1949.; 894961 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Classics., 1945.; 894960 (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Coney, Donald., 1947-1948.; 894959 (Box 15, Folder 10)
- B - Coney, Donald., 1945-1946.; 894958 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- C - Control accounts., 1942-1948.; 894957 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- G - Cowan Library., 1934-1938.; 894956 (Box 16, Folder 3)
- H - Cowan, Robert G., 1942-1948.; 894955 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- D - Cory, John., 1946-1948.; 894954 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- F - Cory Library., 1930-1932.; 894953 (Box 16, Folder 6)
- A - California State Employees Association., 1945-1946.; 894952 (Box 16, Folder 7)
- I - Curriculum., 1944.; 894951 (Box 16, Folder 8)
- J, K, D., 1944-1949.; 894950 (Box 16, Folder 9-10)
- L - Devotie Memorial Foundation., 1945-1946.; 894949 (Box 16, Folder 11)
- M - Devotie Memorial Foundation, Dawson Project., 1948-1949.; 894948 (Box 16, Folder 12)
- N - E., 1944-1947.; 894947 (Box 16, Folder 13)
- O - E., 1947-1949.; 894946 (Box 16, Folder 14)
- P - Eastern trip., 1946 Jun.; 894945 (Box 16, Folder 15)
- Q - Economics., 1937-1948.; 894944 (Box 16, Folder 16)
- R - Education., 1937-1947.; 894943 (Box 16, Folder 17)
- S - Engineering., 1944-1949.; 894942 (Box 16, Folder 18)
- Engineering Library., 1945-1949.; 894941 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- English., 1944-1949.; 894940 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Erslev Library., 1930-1931.; 894939 (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Exhibits, Rilke., 1943.; 894938 (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Exhibits., 1938-1947.; 894937 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Expense and equipment., 1944-1948.; 894936 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Extension Division., 1944-1948.; 894935 (Box 17, Folder 7)
- F., 1944-1949.; 894934 (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Faculty., 1940-1944.; 894933 (Box 17, Folder 9)
- Faculty, Library Conference on Government Publications., 1949.; 894932 (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Farmington Plan., 1947.; 894931 (Box 17, Folder 11)
- Faculty publications., 1940-1942.; 894930 (Box 17, Folder 12)
- Fernald texts., 1943-1945.; 894929 (Box 17, Folder 13)
- Film in Library use., 1949.; 894928 (Box 17, Folder 14)
- Fiske Library., 1925-1927.; 894927 (Box 17, Folder 15)
- Folklore., 1942-1946.; 894926 (Box 17, Folder 16)
- Foreign periodicals in microfilms., 1942-1945.; 894925 (Box 17, Folder 17)
- French., 1938-1949.; 894924 (Box 17, Folder 18)
- Furniture., 1939-1941.; 894923 (Box 17, Folder 19)
- Correspondence, Vosper., 1926-1950.; 894922 (Box 17, Folder 20)
- G., 1944-1946.; 894921 (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Geography., 1938-1949.; 894920 (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Geology., 1939-1947.; 894919 (Box 18, Folder 3)
- German., 1936-1948.; 894918 (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Gifts., 1948-1949.; 894917 (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Unspecified materials, includes physical education publications., 1930-1976.; 894916 (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Goodwin, John E., librarian., 1939-1944.; 894915 (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Graduate Division., 1944-1948.; 894914 (Box 19, Folder 2)
- H., 1944-1950.; 894913 (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Hagan, Jeannette., 1951-1953.; 894912 (Box 19, Folder 4)
- Havet Library., 1925.; 894911 (Box 19, Folder 5)
- History., 1930-1949.; 894910 (Box 19, Folder 6)
- History of Art Fund., 1944-1945.; 894909 (Box 19, Folder 7)
- History of Science., 1942-1945.; 894908 (Box 19, Folder 8)
- Hole Collection., 1940-1950.; 894907 (Box 19, Folder 9)
- Hoffman Library., 1929-1931.; 894906 (Box 19, Folder 10)
- Housing., 1946-1948.; 894905 (Box 19, Folder 11)
- I., 1944-1950.; 894904 (Box 19, Folder 12-13)
- Industrial Relations., 1947-1950.; 894903 (Box 20, Folder 1)
- Institute of Industrial Relations., 1946-1949.; 894902 (Box 20, Folder 2)
- Inter-Library loans., 1924-1949.; 894901 (Box 20, Folder 3-4)
- Inventory (print collections only)., 1933-1944.; 894900 (Box 20, Folder 5)
- J., 1944-1946.; 894899 (Box 20, Folder 6)
- Keys, 1948-1949.; 894898 (Box 20, Folder 7)
- Kluge Library., 1927-1930.; 894897 (Box 20, Folder 8)
- Kock Library., 1934-1936.; 894896 (Box 20, Folder 9)
- L., 1944-1950.; 894895 (Box 20, Folder 10-12)
- Latin American resources., 1945-1948.; 894894 (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Latin American Film Project., 1948-1950.; 894893 (Box 21, Folder 2)
- Latin American official gazettes., 1947-1948.; 894892 (Box 21, Folder 3)
- Law Library., 1947-1949.; 894891 (Box 21, Folder 4)
- Lending code (visiting scholars)., 1947-1948.; 894890 (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Lending code (requests for cards)., 1949-1950.; 894889 (Box 21, Folder 6)
- Letters and Science, College of., 1946-1949.; 894888 (Box 21, Folder 7)
- Letters and Science, Dean., 1948.; 894887 (Box 21, Folder 8)
- Library of Congress., 1939-1949.; 894886 (Box 21, Folder 9)
- Library of Congress cooperative mission (postwar)., 1944-1946.; 894885 (Box 21, Folder 10)
- Library of Congress proof sheet catalog., 1947-1949.; 894884 (Box 21, Folder 11)
- Library Council, Berkeley, Citrus and Davis, 1946-1949.; 894883 (Box 21, Folder 12-14)
- Library Council meeting including interLibrary service, Los Angeles., 1949 May 13.; 894880 (Box 22, Folder 1-2)
- Library Council, Mt. Hamilton, San Francisco, and Santa Barbara. Travel., 1947-1949.; 894878 (Box 22, Folder 3-6)
- Manuscript and archive., 894874 (Box 22, Folder 7)
- Music., 894873 (Box 22, Folder 8)
- Music catalog., 1948-1949.; 894872 (Box 22, Folder 9)
- Music Library., 1940-1950.; 894871 (Box 22, Folder 10-12)
- N., 1944-1950.; 894870 (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
- Naval Science., 1944-1946.; 894869 (Box 23, Folder 3)
- Navy bookroom., 1945.; 894868 (Box 23, Folder 4)
- Newspaper collection., 1945-1951.; 894867 (Box 23, Folder 5-6)
- News service., 1945-1949.; 894866 (Box 23, Folder 7)
- Occidental College., 1942-1948.; 894865 (Box 23, Folder 8)
- O., 1947-1950.; 894864 (Box 23, Folder 9)
- Office of Price Administration records., 1944-1946.; 894863 (Box 23, Folder 10)
- P., 1944-1950.; 894862 (Box 23, Folder 11-12)
- Library, Los Angeles., 1948.; 894861 (Box 24, Folder 1)
- Pamphlets., 1946.; 894860 (Box 24, Folder 2)
- P.A.S. administrative survey., 1946-1948.; 894859 (Box 24, Folder 3)
- Parish Library., 1939.; 894858 (Box 24, Folder 4)
- Parking permits., 1948-1949.; 894857 (Box 24, Folder 5)
- Personnel bulletin., 1946-1947.; 894856 (Box 24, Folder 6)
- Personnel rules., 1947 Oct.; 894855 (Box 24, Folder 7)
- Philosophy., 1948-1949.; 894854 (Box 24, Folder 8)
- Photostats., 1945.; 894853 (Box 24, Folder 9)
- Physical Education, men and women., 1936-1949.; 894852 (Box 24, Folder 10)
- Physics., 1937-1945.; 894851 (Box 24, Folder 11)
- Political Science., 1938-1948.; 894850 (Box 24, Folder 12)
- Point Loma., 1941.; 894849 (Box 24, Folder 13)
- Post-War buying., 1945-1947.; 894848 (Box 24, Folder 14)
- Princeton conference., 1946.; 894847 (Box 24, Folder 15)
- Printing requisitions., 1945-1950.; 894846 (Box 24, Folder 16)
- Psychology., 1944-1947.; 894845 (Box 24, Folder 17)
- Public health nursing., 1946-1947.; 894844 (Box 24, Folder 18)
- Q., 1945-1949.; 894843 (Box 24, Folder 19)
- R., 1944-1950.; 894842 (Box 24, Folder 20-22)
- Ralph D. Reed Library. Guide to geological literature., 1947.; 894841 (Box 24, Folder 23)
- Rare books inquiry., 1949-1950.; 894840 (Box 24, Folder 24)
- Receiving Department., 1946-1949.; 894839 (Box 24, Folder 25)
- Reference., 1941-1949.; 894838 (Box 25, Folder 1-2)
- Reinhardt Library., 1946-1950.; 894837 (Box 25, Folder 3)
- Registrar., 1946.; 894836 (Box 25, Folder 4)
- Rental., 1935-1942.; 894835 (Box 25, Folder 5)
- Requests., 1929.; 894834 (Box 25, Folder 6)
- Research Committee., 1924-1929.; 894833 (Box 25, Folder 7)
- Reserve book room., 1936-1946.; 894832 (Box 25, Folder 8)
- Resources of UCLA Library., 1941-1944.; 894831 (Box 25, Folder 9)
- Russian duplicates., 1948.; 894830 (Box 25, Folder 10)
- S., 1942-1951.; 894829 (Box 25, Folder 11-13)
- Slavic Project., 1946-1949.; 894828 (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Sociology., 1945.; 894827 (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Spanish., 1938.; 894826 (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Spanish and Italian., 1945-1947.; 894825 (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Special Collections., 1939; n.d.; 894824 (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Special Libraries Association., 1948-1950.; 894823 (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Spinoza Collection., 1950.; 894822 (Box 26, Folder 7-8)
- Staff Association., 1944-1949.; 894821 (Box 26, Folder 9)
- Staff handbook., 1940-1947.; 894820 (Box 26, Folder 10)
- Staff privileges., 1926-1941.; 894819 (Box 26, Folder 11)
- State publications., 1946.; 894818 (Box 26, Folder 12)
- Students., 1934-1949.; 894817 (Box 26, Folder 13)
- Student handbook., 1946-1948.; 894816 (Box 26, Folder 14)
- Student Library Committee., 1945-1949.; 894815 (Box 27, Folder 1)
- Study halls., 1947-1948.; 894814 (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Subscriptions to added copies of periodicals., 1949.; 894813 (Box 27, Folder 3)
- Supplies., 1930-1944.; 894812 (Box 27, Folder 4)
- T., 1943-1950.; 894811 (Box 27, Folder 5-7)
- Telegrams., 1941-1944.; 894810 (Box 27, Folder 8)
- Thomason tracts., 1948.; 894809 (Box 27, Folder 9)
- Travel expense., 1944-1949.; 894808 (Box 27, Folder 10)
- U., 1944-1945; 1948-1950.; 894807 (Box 27, Folder 11-12)
- U.S. Government documents depository., 1923-1939.; 894806 (Box 27, Folder 13)
- United Nations., 1948-1949.; 894805 (Box 27, Folder 14)
- University Elementary School., 1944-1949.; 894804 (Box 27, Folder 15)
- University libraries statistics., 1920-1950.; 894803 (Box 27, Folder 16)
- University Press., 1945-1949.; 894802 (Box 27, Folder 17)
- Unpurchased collections., 1936-1942.; 894801 (Box 28, Folder 1)
- V., 1944-1950.; 894800 (Box 28, Folder 2-3)
- Vacation schedules., 1944-1947.; 894799 (Box 28, Folder 4)
- Veterans' Affairs., 1946-1949.; 894798 (Box 28, Folder 5)
- Vocational Conference., 1947-1949.; 894797 (Box 28, Folder 6)
- W., 1944-1950.; 894796 (Box 28, Folder 7-8)
- Want lists., 1945.; 894795 (Box 28, Folder 9)
- War Relocation Authority., 1945.; 894794 (Box 28, Folder 10)
- War safe-guards., 1941-1949.; 894793 (Box 28, Folder 11)
- Appointment books., 1949-1963.; 894792 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  Scope and Content
  Includes 13 books.
- Western Regional Libraries., 1947.; 894791 (Box 30, Folder 1)
- Unspecified materials., 1941-1942; 1944.; 894790 (Box 30, Folder 2)
- Wilt, David - purchasing., 1944-1948.; 894789 (Box 30, Folder 3)
- Works Progress Administration., 1936-1940.; 894788 (Box 30, Folder 4)
- Work week., 1946.; 894787 (Box 30, Folder 5)
- Wreden, William P., 1947-1950.; 894786 (Box 30, Folder 6)
- X-Y-Z., 1944-1946.; 894785 (Box 30, Folder 7)
- X-YZ., 1946-1950.; 894784 (Box 30, Folder 8)
- Zoology., 1938; 1945-1949.; 894783 (Box 30, Folder 9-10)
- Lawrence Clark Powell's appointment books., 1949-1963.; 894782 (Box 30, Folder 11)
- Powell - Guggenheim., 1948-1955.; 894781 (Box 30, Folder 12)
- Powell - history., 1950-1951.; 894780 (Box 30, Folder 13)
- Powell - L.A. Times article., 1950.; 894779 (Box 30, Folder 14)
- Unspecified material., 1950-1951.; 894778 (Box 31, Folder 1)
- Powell to H. Richard Archer - European book buying., 1950-1951.; 894777 (Box 31, Folder 2)
- Powell to H. Richard Archer., 1950-1951.; 894776 (Box 31, Folder 3)
- European book buying trip, invoices., 1950-1951.; 894775 (Box 31, Folder 4)
- Powell - London., 1950-1951.; 894774 (Box 31, Folder 5)
- L.C. Powell - England., 1957.; 894773 (Box 31, Folder 6)
- Itinerary for Powell., 1950 Feb-Jun.; 894772 (Box 31, Folder 7)
- The Beaucamp Book Shop., 1950-1951.; 894771 (Box 31, Folder 8)
- Booksellers., 1950-1951.; 894770 (Box 31, Folder 9)
- Bradstreet., 1950-1951.; 894769 (Box 32, Folder 1)
- California Library Association., 1950-1951.; 894768 (Box 32, Folder 2)
- Edwards, H. W., 1950.; 894767 (Box 32, Folder 3)
- Folger., 1950-1951.; 894766 (Box 32, Folder 4)
- Receipts., 1950-1951.; 894765 (Box 32, Folder 5)
- Clark invoices., 894764 (Box 32, Folder 6)
- Rota, Bertram., 894763 (Box 32, Folder 7)
- Sims, G. F., 1950-1951.; 894762 (Box 32, Folder 8)
- Smith, John E., 1950-1951.; 894761 (Box 32, Folder 9)
- Unspecified materials., 1960.; 894760 (Box 32, Folder 10)
- L.C. Powell - invoices., 1960.; 894759 (Box 32, Folder 11)
- Europe buying trip - report by L.C. Powell., 1958.; 894758 (Box 32, Folder 12)
- Unspecified material., 1957-1958.; 894757 (Box 32, Folder 13)
- Powell - account records, trip abroad., 1960.; 894756 (Box 32, Folder 14)
- Berkeley - policy, english literature, history of science, buying list., 1957.; 894755 (Box 32, Folder 15-17)
- Unspecified material., 1957.; 894752 (Box 32, Folder 18)
- Stevens-Brown., 1950-1951.; 894751 (Box 33, Folder 1)
- Unesco., 1950-1951.; 894750 (Box 33, Folder 2)
- Robert Vosper (Dr. Powell on leave)., 1950-1951.; 894749 (Box 33, Folder 3)
- Want lists., 1947-1951.; 894748 (Box 33, Folder 4)
- A-Z correspondence., 1949-1951.; 894747 (Box 33, Folder 5)
- A-P., 1948-1950.; 894746 (Box 34, Folder 1)
- R-Z., 1948-1950.; 894745 (Box 35, Folder 1)
- A-H., 1950-1951.; 894744 (Box 35, Folder 2)
- I-Z., 1950-1951.; 894743 (Box 36, Folder 1)
- A-C., 1951-1952.; 894742 (Box 36, Folder 2)
- D-R., 1951-1952.; 894741 (Box 37, Folder 1)
- S-Z., 1951-1952.; 894740 (Box 38, Folder 1)
- Administrative Council., 1956.; 894739 (Box 38, Folder 2)
- E-S., 1952-1953.; 894738 (Box 39, Folder 1)
- T-Z., 1952-1953.; 894737 (Box 40, Folder 1)
- A-J., 1953-1954.; 894736 (Box 40, Folder 2)
- K-Z., 1953-1954.; 894735 (Box 41, Folder 1)
- A-G., 1954-1955.; 894734 (Box 41, Folder 2)
- H-Z., 1954-1955.; 894733 (Box 42, Folder 1)
- A-L., 1955-1956.; 894732 (Box 43, Folder 1)
- M-Z., 1955-1956.; 894731 (Box 44, Folder 1)
- List of material formerly housed in the Library Administrative Office., 1949-1958.; 894730 (Box 45, Folder 1)
- Academic Senate - Memorials Committee., 1954-1958.; 894729 (Box 45, Folder 2)
- Acquisitions., 1949-1955.; 894728 (Box 45, Folder 3)
- Added book copies., 1945-1947.; 894727 (Box 45, Folder 4)
- Administrative Committee., 1950-1952.; 894726 (Box 45, Folder 5)
- Administrative Advisory Council., 1951-1953.; 894725 (Box 45, Folder 6)
- Altman, Fred., 1954-1958.; 894724 (Box 45, Folder 7)
- Altman Collection, proposed., 1953-1955.; 894723 (Box 45, Folder 8)
- American Association of University Professors., 1949-1953.; 894722 (Box 45, Folder 9)
- American Council on Education Project., 1949.; 894721 (Box 45, Folder 10)
- American Library Association., 1948-1955.; 894720 (Box 45, Folder 11)
- American Library Association - ALA bulletin., 1952-1955.; 894719 (Box 45, Folder 12)
- American Library Association - Committee on Out of Print Books., 1948-1959.; 894718; Includes Committee on Out of Print Books, Conferences, and Nominating Committee (Box 46, Folder 1-4)
- Architect's Office - remodelling., 894714 (Box 46, Folder 5)
- Architect's Office - Stack Annex., 894713 (Box 46, Folder 6)
- Argus Book Shop., 1948-1953.; 894712 (Box 46, Folder 7)
- Association of College and Reference Libraries., 1946-1955.; 894711; Includes Meetings, Nominating Committee, Budget SubComiittee (Box 46, Folder 8-11)
- Association of Research Libraries - meetings, reports., 1947-1957.; 894707; Includes meetings, reports, projects. (Box 47, Folder 1-5)
- Atomic Energy Commission Despository., 1954.; 894704 (Box 47, Folder 6)
- Barja Collection., 1957-1960.; 894703 (Box 47, Folder 7)
- Belt Library bookplates., 1961-1962.; 894702 (Box 47, Folder 8)
- Berkeley - correspondence, lists of Library personnel., 1947-1954.; 894701 (Box 47, Folder 9)
- Berkeley School of Librarianship, 1944-1948; 894700 (Box 47, Folder 10-15)
- Bibliographic Asst. to Librarian., 1956.; 894697 (Box 48, Folder 6)
- Bibliographic Society of America Council, Powell as President, meetings., 1948-1959.; 894696 (Box 48, Folder 7-10)
- Bibliographical Society of America meetings and Powell as President., 1955-1957.; 894692 (Box 49, Folder 1-3)
- Bibliographies - communism., 1951-1954.; 894689 (Box 49, Folder 4)
- British Empire Project., 1944-1950.; 894688 (Box 49, Folder 5)
- Brookings Institution., 1959.; 894687 (Box 49, Folder 6)
- Buildings and grounds., 1950-1955.; 894686 (Box 49, Folder 7)
- Bunche, Ralph., 1954.; 894685 (Box 49, Folder 8)
- Business Office., 1948-1949; 1954-1955.; 894684 (Box 49, Folder 9)
- Bynum, Lindley, correspondence., 1952-1957.; 894683 (Box 49, Folder 10)
- California Library Association., 1949-1953.; 894682 (Box 49, Folder 11)